David Sánchez Martín

Head of Business Insights

🦍 Madrid

+34 635386308

davidchepe@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidsanchez-martin/

PROFILE

Experienced Data & Analytics Leader, helping to unlock business value in different companies since 2006. Competent in managing a multidisciplinary (bi developers, data engineers, business analysts and project managers) international, delocalized team. Ability to work effectively with stakeholders at all levels of the organization

EDUCATION

Sep. 2017- Master Data Scientist

May. 2018 KSchool

Dec. 2004 - Industrial Organization Engineer

Sep. 2002 Valladolid University

Sep. 1997 - Electrical Engineer

Jun. 2002 Valladolid University

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Head of Group BI B2Holding. Jan. 2022 - Today

Spain

Responsible of the Global BI strategy for the Headquarters, aligning developments, priorities and activating assets through the 22 countries of the Group

The main achievement in this role is the transformation of the way in which we make decisions in the Group, moving from an old-fashioned BI tool to a new environment full cloud based. This has not been only a technical challenge, but also a chance to improve our making decisions process

Data&Analytics Manager B2Holding-Spain. Dec. 2020 – Jun. 2022

Spain

Working in the Spanish branch of the B2Holding Group I was in charge of the whole data and analytics team, supporting the Operations team in developing their strategies. As a result of this new strategies, we achieved for the first time in the history to rank in the first position for 6 times in a row Apart from that I was part of the Group Executive Team leading the company and influencing in all decisions

Bl Manager Altamira/doValue. Jan. 2019 – Dec. 2020

Spain

Leader of the Secured Assets reporting area in the company. The main achievement was to develop a new reporting suite working together with the CEO office to ensure the adoption of the new developments. The new developments included also predictive models integrated with the traditional BI reports.

SKILLS

BI SKILLS

 Microsoft PowerBI, Tableau, QlikView, SAP Business Objects

IT SKILLS

Python, SQL, Azure

LANGUAGES

English: B2/C1

ACHIEVEMENTS

B2Holding:

 Migration from IBM ecosystem to MS Azure Reducing the number of reports by 6. From 300 to 50.

B2Holding Spain:

Increase in Revenues by 2.
 Thanks to a strategy change resulting in 6 times in a row winning month for Bank Sadadell

DoValue (Former Altamira):

 Deployment of PowerBI, increasing the use of BI reports by 10. Reaching 1000 views per month just for the main Dashboard (with only 20 users)

CERTIFICATIONS

PMI:

 Project Management Officer. Jul-2013

Project Manager Prosegur. Apr. 2015 – Jan. 2019

Spain

The main role in Prosegur was to be an internal promoter of the Data and Analytics team. I was in charge of establishing the relationships with existing and new stakeholders in the organization to be sure that every single decision in the company was data-driven

Account Manager Keyrus. Jan. 2014 - Apr. 2015

Spain

Change in role developing the new BI practices. Keyrus was an ETL/DB specialized company. As Account Manager I bring to the company two more clients and developed the new BI projects in many other ones. Technologies used were QlikView, Oracle BI, Sap Business Objects, Xcelsius and Tableau

Project Manager Keyrus. Jul. 2012 – Dec. 2013

Spair

Leadership in a multinational project involving my bigñgest Team so far. Stakeholders were scattered across multiple countries like US, Ireland, Poland, India and France. The development team was composed by almost 10 people in the highest peak including Data Architects, Data Engineers, BI Developers, Business Analysts and Testers.

BI Manager SDG Consulting. Jan. 2011 - Jul. 2012

Spain

In addition to the technical tasks, I was assuming bigger responsibilities in the Management team of the office helping also in the acquisition and integration of another company in our Team.

Natural evolution of the role, leading globally clients and practices. Accountable for the client P&L, with objectives based on new accounts opened, revenues and margin.

BI Senior Consultant SDG Consulting. Jan. 2008 – Dec. 2010

Spain

In charge of whole projects or even small clients from end to end. This includes not only ensuring the technical excellence of the projects delivered but also developing the team and taking care of the revenue of the projects/clients.

Bigger role in the commercial area leading the internal selling in the clients in which I was working.

About the team development, I was in charge of the recruiting and training of my own team.

BI Consultant SDG Consulting. Jan. 2006 – Dec. 2007

Spair

Business Intelligence consultant in charge of developing different projects, ranging from pure Business Intelligence to more Business oriented such as Budgeting Processes, Demand Planning among others.

Taking part since the very beginning in the commercial phases helping in the elaboration of offers and acting like a pre-sales engineer.

SKILLS

BI SKILLS

 Microsoft PowerBI, Tableau, QlikView, SAP Business Objects

IT SKILLS

Python, SQL